ARIMA KINEN
(有馬紀念)
One race left.
剩下一場比賽…
The next race
下一場比賽
will be my final race in Twinkle Series.
就是我在閃光系列賽中的 最後一場比賽
Her performance is back.
有跑出時間來
She's burning whatever is left in her to deliver the best performance.
犧牲自我 有著燃燒生命般覺悟的跑法嗎…
I'll run another lap.
我再去跑一趟
Crown?
皇冠
Good luck.
請加油
Kitasan is very motivated today.
北部今天也很拼呢
She'll regret it if her last performance is less than spectacular.
如果只是"跑出一場好比賽" 那肯定會留下遺憾的
That's why she's training so hard.
所以她才會如此拼命掙扎
You can't lose to her, Cheval.
妳也不能輸給她呢 駿逸
I will not.
當然了
Are you all right, Kitasan?
還好嗎 北部
Yes, I'm fine.
是…當然沒問題…
Let's call it a day here.
今天到此為止
Go back and rest after you're done stretching.
做完緩和運動後就回去吧
Noted. Thanks a lot!
是…是的 辛苦了…
Is there something I can do for Kitasan?
真想為北部做些什麼呢
Right? I feel the same way too.
是啊 真想為她做些什麼啊
"EPISODE 13: AND SO YOU…"
(第13話 於是妳的…)
What can I do for her?
真想為她做些什麼呢
What can I do…
真想為她做些什麼…
Hmm…
真想給她些什麼呢…
What can I do for her?
真想為她做點什麼
Hi, everyone.
辛苦了
Hi, Kitasan.
啊 北部 辛苦了
Here. Your special drink.
給妳 這是特製飲料
We're using a special recipe today.
今天也是特別配方喔
Thank you.
謝謝大家
All of you are always so supportive.
大家真的每天都這樣幫我…
Don't mention it.
不用跟我們客氣
Hmm. We will always be there for you.
是啊 我們都會幫妳的
Guys…
各位…
I'm so happy to be part of Spica.
我能加入Spica 真的是太好了
Do you have something you want?
妳有什麼想要的東西嗎
Uhm…
這樣的話…
Can I ask you for a favour?
我想到一件事 想要拜託妳們
Have you checked out the mid-fan voting presentation?
你看過粉絲投票的中間發表了嗎
Yes, Kitasan Black has the highest number of votes.
看了 北部玄駒的得票數最高呢
"ARIMA KINEN, DECEMBER 24TH" I did not expect anything less.
(有馬紀念 12月24日) 也是啦 說當然也是理所當然的
"ARIMA KINEN SPECIAL: KITASAN'S LAST RACE" In Takarazuka and Arima,
(有馬紀念特輯 北部玄駒引退賽) 在寶塚及有馬紀念時
she was voted the fans' favourite,
每次都會被粉絲投票選出
"KITASAN BLACK QUITS AFTER ARIMA KINEN"
(北部玄駒將在有馬紀念裡光榮引退)
but she failed to win the race.
(北部玄駒將在有馬紀念裡完美結束) 但在大獎賽時總是贏不了呢
"KITASAN BLACK IN TIP-TOP SHAPE" She has already won several G1.
(北部玄駒 狀態絕佳) 她明明贏下了好幾個GI
I hope she wins her last one.
真希望她能在這最後一戰獲勝
I'm sure Kitasan Black can win in Arima Kinen.
這場有馬紀念 北部玄駒肯定沒問題的
I doubt she'll be in bad shape.
她的狀況應該不會太差才對
She almost won Japan Cup back then too.
在日本盃時也是差點就贏了
Yeah.
是啊
Despite losing the race, she had the lead during the early stage.
雖然最後被超越了 但依然是那個北部的領先跑法
We won't be able to see her run anymore.
但是…以後就看不到了
What a shame.
真令人感到失落啊
Yeah, it's her last match. I can't miss out.
是啊 這是最後一場比賽了 絕對不能錯過呢
Hmm.
說得也是
We will do our best to cheer for her. Leave no regrets!
我們要用盡全力為她加油 不要留下遺憾
Yes!
當然了
My husband and I will be in Nakayama Racecourse to watch the race.
比賽當天 我要跟我老公一起去中山競馬場
Me too!
哎呀 太太 我也是耶
I just need to be there for her.
果然還是想親眼去看呢
My husband rewatched all her races, starting from her debut race.
我老公他啊 把北部玄駒的比賽 從新馬出道賽從頭看了一遍呢
My husband did that too.
真是的 我家也是…
How popular do you think she'll be on that day?
你覺得她當天的人氣會如何
The most popular one, of course.
那當然肯定是第一名嘛
Right.
也是
She'll end her journey with a bang.
最後謝幕一定要是漂亮結束才行嘛
I'm sure Kitasan can do it.
如果是北部的話 一定辦得到的
Dad, will Kita win?
爸爸 小北會贏嗎
I think she will.
那當然 她一定會贏的
She will train very hard to win the race.
我想她一定在為了獲勝 而拼命練習的
Then I'll cheer very hard for her too!
那我也要拼命為她加油
I have always yearned
我一直憧憬著
and longed to create
一直夢想著
a festive scene.
那個像是祭典般的景色
I was so close,
那個還差一點就能到達的…
but
那個風景
I failed.
我沒能創造出來…
However,
但是…
I must give my best performance for those who have been cheering for me.
我要比出一場最棒的比賽 獻給一直為我加油的人們
I want them to watch my final race with a smile.
為了讓大家用笑容送我一程
Kita.
小北
Teio.
帝皇
Good job today.
辛苦了
Everyone is working very hard to make your wish come true.
小北的那個心願 大家都很賣力喔
Thank you.
謝謝妳們
The day has come.
終於到了呢
Yes.
是
Finally.
終於到了
I… want to win.
我…想要贏
This is my last race.
這是最後一場比賽了
I must win it.
我絕對要贏
I see.
這樣啊…
I'm sure everyone thinks that way.
我想大家也都是一樣的想法吧
No one runs to lose.
沒有人會抱著必敗的想法參賽的
Still, there can only be one winner.
但即便如此 能贏的人還是只有一個
However, I'm sure the winner
不過 能獲勝的人
belongs to someone who perseveres
肯定是無論再怎麼難受 再怎麼痛苦
till the very end, regardless
還能憑著不輸給任何人的堅強信念
of how challenging and daunting the circumstances are.
比所有人都能拼到最後的人吧
I see that in you, Kitasan.
這些我都看在眼裡喔
You never give up.
看著那個永不放棄 堅持到底的小北
Teio…
帝皇…
Yeah!
是
The end of the year is nigh. Today is Christmas Eve.
年終將至 今天是平安夜
"G1, ARIMA KINEN, NAKAYAMA, 2,500M LAP" The end of the year is nigh. Today is Christmas Eve.
(GI 有馬紀念 中山 草地2500公尺)
"G1, ARIMA KINEN, NAKAYAMA, 2,500M LAP" During this festive season,
在街上洋溢佳節氣氛之時
Arima Kinen will unfold in Nakayama Racecourse.
中山競馬場 將要開始有馬紀念的比賽
We have gathered a stellar lineup today.
今年的參賽者也是高手如雲
Who will win the final grand event of the year?
究竟年末大獎賽的榮耀 會落在誰的手上呢
I can't wait to find out.
每年都令人興奮不已呢
Me too.
是啊
I'm sure those watching the live broadcast
就連透過轉播觀看這場比賽的觀眾
can feel the heat and the passion at the scene too.
肯定也能感受到 現場滿溢而出的熱情與心意
I'll be reporting before the horse station in Nakayama Racecourse today.
今天在這個中山競馬場 的馬匹檢閱場前來為大家進行播報
Let's go!
好
Which horse girl
究竟是哪一位賽馬娘
will play Santa Claus and deliver the present
能夠代替聖誕老人 將名為勝利的禮物送給
to more than 100,000 spectators here?
這超過十萬人的觀眾呢
This is the moment.
終於來了呢
The race will begin shortly.
比賽即將開始
Kitasan, you look awesome.
北…北部 妳太帥了…
I love it.
太好了
It's perfect on you.
很適合妳
Thanks a lot.
各位 謝謝妳們
It's rare to see Kitasan in short pants.
看到北部穿短褲還真是新奇
Do you like it? It's perfect for running.
不錯吧 感覺很便於奔跑
The cape was my idea.
那個披風可是我的主意喔
The shoulder pad is beautiful too.
肩帶也很漂亮
You look like a leader.
有領導者的感覺
Right? That's my idea.
不錯吧 那是我想的
You can't even see my design on the uniform…
上面找不到我的設計…
Thank you for designing my uniform.
有請大家幫忙真是太好了
-My design… -I will complete the race for Spica.
-我的設計… -我會背負Spica的信念 奔跑到最後
Hmm…
喔…
I wish I had this treatment too when I was going through this.
真希望我那個時候 也有這種待遇
Quit complaining.
不要抱怨
I know it sounds weird,
雖然這樣說有點怪
but please, come back safely.
但妳要平安回來喔
Okay.
是
Here I go then.
那我就出發了
All athletes are waiting for the signal at their gates.
好的 所有選手都在草地上 等待比賽的開始
Sounds of Earth is the runner-up for three G1 races and four G2 races.
萬籟爭鳴至今的戰績為 3次GI第二名 4次GⅡ第二名
She was very close to first place.
都是只差臨門一腳就能獲勝
We can't judge her based on her recent performance,
雖然不能用最近的成績來看待她
but let's see if she can get her first trophy
但還是來期待她 是否能在年末的有馬紀念裡
at the end of the year.
奪下第一個GI冠軍吧
Good luck, Earth!
加油啊 爭鳴
She looks
看她那個樣子
very confident.
看來她很沉著呢
Yup.
嘿嘿嗯
Arima Kinen is the final race of the year.
有馬紀念 是一年最後的總結之戰
It is also Kitasan Black's final race.
而且今天還是北部玄駒的引退賽
Now is the best opportunity to make herself known.
在這極度這備受矚目舞台 是留下自身足跡的絕佳機會
You can do this, Earth.
妳可以的 妳一定辦得到的 爭鳴
Speaking of trophies, I feel compelled to mention the champion
說到奪下GI冠軍 就不能不提到在日前贏下日本盃
of Japan Cup, Cheval Grand. She is here with us today too.
拿下其榮耀的高尚駿逸 也參與了這次的比賽
Will she show us the deadly acceleration she did in Japan Cup?
今天能讓我們再次見識到 她那贏下日本盃時的精湛加速嗎
The champion of Takarazuka Kinen, Satono Crown, is worthy of note too.
贏下今年寶塚紀念的里見皇冠 也很值得矚目
Can she redeem herself
她能夠在這年末的中山競馬場
in this racecourse?
一雪先前比賽的恥辱嗎
You can do this, Crown!
加油 加油 皇冠
And then, it's the fans' favourite.
然後是我們的人氣王
She deserves her spot in the fans' voting.
粉絲投票首位絕非浪得虛名
She was the Horse Girl of the Year last year.
既是上回的年度代表賽馬娘
If she wins this race, she'll become the horse girl with the most G1 trophies.
要是贏下了這場比賽 也將成為贏下最多GI冠軍選手
Kitasan Black!
北部玄駒
It's her last race.
今天的比賽是她的引退賽
I hope she can retire without any regrets.
希望她能完成一場沒有遺憾的比賽
It's my last race in the Twinkle Series.
這是我最後一次 在閃光系列賽裡比賽了
This anxiety…
開賽前的所有緊張與不安
It'll be my last time feeling it.
也是最後一次了…
All right. It begins now.
好的 終於要開始了
The final grand prix of the year.
今年的集大成 年末大獎賽
Arima Kinen.
有馬紀念
On this wintry day, determined horse girls
在寒空之下 內心充滿鬥志的賽馬娘們
enter the horse gates accordingly.
正陸續走進閘門就位
Their stage is ready.
舞台已備妥
The end-of-year grand prix, Arima Kinen.
年末大獎賽 有馬紀念
UMA MUSUME PRETTY DERBY SEASON 3
《賽馬娘 Pretty Derby 第三季》
It starts now!
比賽開始
Kitasan Black is off to a good start, as usual.
北部玄駒的起跑仍舊相當漂亮
She's leading on the inside line.
領先的是內側的北部玄駒
She has a solid lead.
馬上就取得了領先地位
But 2,500 meters is a long journey.
2500公尺的賽程還很遙遠
Kitasan Black continues to lead.
北部玄駒領先
There are six bends in this racecourse.
在小圈的中山競馬場裡 共有六個彎道
They blitzed by the first one and are now charging at the second.
首先通過第一個 現在衝向第二彎道
She's off to a good start.
起跑還不錯
That's right.
是啊
Keep it up!
好 就這樣往前衝
All the best, Kitasan.
加油 北部
Kitasan Black is in the lead.
北部玄駒領先
Moon Hero takes the second place.
第二名是明月英雄
Coming from the flank is another veteran, Canon Millefeuille.
外側的是資深賽馬娘 卡農千層
On the inside line is Crescent Ace.
內側則是新月王牌
Behind her is It's Calling.
在她後面的是當前呼喚
Read Poetry tails behind her
在她的後方 閱覽詩歌也緊追不放
while Sounds of Earth is in last place.
萬籟爭鳴則是在最後方
All 16 horse girls are passing by the spectator stands.
16名選手的勇姿 通過觀眾席前
Everyone is waiting for her.
觀眾都在等著她
Kitasan Black, it's her final race.
北部玄駒 這將是她的最後一戰
Let's look at the big screen.
現在通過賽場螢幕
She must have seen the lap time.
她應該看到計時時間了
How is the race? How is her pace?
賽況如何 步調如何
Did she give her all?
自己有沒有發揮出實力
The first 1,000 meters is completed in 61.6 seconds.
最初的1000公尺 成績為61秒6
Not bad. It's her usual pace.
不錯 有跑出自己的步調
That's right.
是啊
She has the lead, as usual.
領先在前 是她一貫的跑法
Hmm.
就是啊
But she seems to be in pain.
但她好像有一點痛苦
What?
是這樣嗎
If I relax a bit…
要是有絲毫鬆懈的話…
If I slow down…
要是慢了其他人一步的話…
If someone catches up to me…
要是被人追平的話…
I must…
所以…
I'm watching Kita's race with everyone.
像這樣跟大家一起來看小北的比賽 今天就是…
I wish to stay in this moment forever.
真想一直就這樣看下去啊
Kita has become part of our life.
因為小北已經像是 我們生活的一部分了
Let's memorize this moment.
好好將她烙印在眼底吧
Save your lament for later.
傷心難過的話之後再說
Kita is doing her best out there.
小北現在正在用盡全力在比賽
We must cheer loudly for her.
我們要為她加油才行
Right.
是啊
Kitasan Black controls the pace of the race.
比賽節奏完全被北部玄駒掌握
This is her final race.
這就是她的最後一戰
Can she give her career the perfect ending?
她能夠為比賽生涯畫上完美句號嗎
The second place, Moon Hero, is chasing after her.
第二名是明月英雄 依然緊追不放
Crescent Ace is on the inside line.
內側是新月王牌
At the flank, Canon Millefeuille has her eyes on Kitasan too.
外側的卡農千層不斷緊盯著她
Behind them are It's Calling and Read Poetry at the flank.
再來後方是當前呼喚 以及外側的閱覽詩歌
Chronicles is on the inside line. Black Ebony is in the middle.
內側是編年史誓約 中央是黑色檀木
Cheval Grand is on the flank. She's here.
外側是高尚駿逸 她在這裡
The winner of Japan Cup is here.
贏下日本盃的高尚駿逸 現在在這個位置
Behind her
在她的後方
is the winner of Takarazuka Kinen, Satono Crown.
就是贏下寶塚紀念的賽馬娘 里見皇冠
Next to her is Ribbon Training.
而她的外側就是緞帶練習曲
Kitasan Black…
北部玄駒…
I want to surpass you.
我要再度超越妳…
I will realize my dream to win consecutively.
我要實現大獎賽連霸的夢想
Even when you're gone,
就算妳離開了
I'll continue racing.
我也要繼續我的比賽
On the inside line, behind Original Shine is Seventh Queen.
接著在內側原初閃亮後方的 是第七女王
And then, Sounds of Earth is catching up.
再來就是從後方追上的萬籟爭鳴
Six Pack became the last place.
六塊肌現在成為了最後一名
You can do this, Earth.
請加油 爭鳴
All the best, Earth.
加油啊 爭鳴
All the best, Kitasan.
加油啊 北部
Approaching the third bend,
來到第二次的第三彎道
Kitasan Black maintains her lead.
領先的依然是北部玄駒
What will the ones behind her do?
在她後方的賽馬娘會有什麼行動呢
That's Kitasan's style, all right.
這跑法真有她的風格
I agree.
真有她的風格
Yeah.
是啊
She runs with all she has.
那種不顧一切地去拼命
Watching her determination somehow fills me with energy.
彷彿能從她那奮力向前的樣子裡 得到活力的跑法
It's a simple yet awesome way of running.
既笨拙又帥氣
That's Kitasan Black for you.
那就是北部玄駒
The third place on the flank, Read Poetry,
接著在外側的第三名 閱覽詩歌
speeds up.
出手的時機點
Will this be a war of attrition?
這場有馬紀念會變成忍耐大賽嗎
I want to win.
我想贏…
Kitasan Black is here!
北部玄駒來了
Summoning all her willpower,
注入所有的信念
she creates distance with each step she takes.
一步接著一步地大力踏出去
No, you won't!
妳想都別想
Kitasan!
北部…
Step by step. Step by step.
一步接著一步…
Kitasan Black continues to accelerate.
北部玄駒不斷加速
-Go! -You can do this!
-衝啊… -加油啊
Run!
跑起來
Go!
衝啊
It's so close.
只差一點點了
The loud cheer at the scene is shaking the entire racecourse.
眾人的歡呼聲撼動整個中山競馬場
-Keep it up, Kitasan! -The loud cheer at the scene is shaking the entire racecourse.
-好厲害 太強了 加油 北部 -眾人的歡呼聲撼動整個中山競馬場
Keep it up. The finishing line is near.
就這樣向前衝 就快抵達妳的終點了
You can do this.
衝吧
Kita!
小北
Cross the finishing line!
直直衝過去
I love the way she runs!
我好喜歡她這樣跑喔
So brutish yet so inspiring!
既俗氣又拼命
Like us.
就像是我們一樣
I'm having goosebumps.
讓人熱血沸騰
I hope she wins.
我希望她能獲勝
You can do this!
好強…
Go!
衝啊…
Kitasan Black!
北部玄駒
The horse girls behind her pick up their pace.
後方的各賽馬娘急起直追
Cheval Grand is in the middle. Ribbon Training is on the flank.
中間的是高尚駿逸 外側是緞帶練習曲
-What? -Wow!
-什麼… -好強
No one can catch up to her.
沒人能追得上她
They can't even catch her shadow.
連她的影子都追不上
Kitasan Black widens the gap between her and everyone else.
北部玄駒讓後方的人 只能看見她的背影
She's leading by two horse lengths.
領先了兩個馬身
Go!
衝啊…
So this is how a megastar
這就是巨星的…
completes her career!
引退方式啊
Kitasan Black!
北部玄駒
A thunderous cheer erupted in this racecourse.
中山競馬場傳出盛大的歡呼聲
Everyone offers congratulations to Kitasan Black.
所有觀眾為她獻上祝福
Well done!
好強
Well done, Kitasan Black!
北部玄駒太強了
Having crossed the finishing line,
在她奔馳而過的前方
she is met with countless congratulations and applause.
等著她的是感謝以及祝福
All fans present congratulate and thank her.
全場的粉絲紛紛向她表達了 "恭喜"以及"感謝"的歡呼
This is Kitasan Black's 7th G1 victory,
北部玄駒 這是她的GI第7勝
and also her perfect finale.
她畫下了完美的句點
Thank you, Kitasan Black!
謝謝妳…北部玄駒
You're awesome, Kitasan!
妳太強了 北部
I will do my best. I will do my best tomorrow too!
我也會加油的 明天開始會再度加油的
Thank you, Kita!
小北 謝謝妳
What a festival…
是祭典…
Seven victories…
GI7勝…
She has surpassed me as a horse girl.
她成為比我還要厲害的賽馬娘了呢
What a talent.
真是厲害
I knew she could do it.
跟預想的一樣呢
Well done, you.
真的很了不起
The second place remains undetermined. After checking the recording,
僵持不下的第二名爭奪戰 經過照片判定後
we hereby announce that It's Calling was the runner-up.
第二名是當前呼喚
Cheval Grand is the second runner-up.
第三名為高尚駿逸
Kitasan outmaneuvers her opponents in this nail-biter
雖然經過了激烈死鬥 但果然還是北部玄駒技高一籌
and won the race.
完美贏下了比賽
Crown is ranked 13th.
皇冠是第十三名呢
Miss Trainer.
訓練師
Yes?
是
With the tournament next spring as my goal,
我想先以入春時期的比賽為目標
I want to resume my training at the beginning of next year.
等新的一年來臨 就再度開始訓練
Understood.
我明白了
Yes, I must run.
沒錯 奔跑吧
Because
因為
I want to see the view Kitasan has now.
我也想去看看小北所看見的景色
Earth, you did your best.
爭鳴也很努力了
7th place. She has done well.
第七名 我認為她已經表現得很棒了
The cheer is so loud.
好熱烈的歡呼聲喔
It hypes me up too.
連我都興奮起來了
Yeah.
是啊
Her last race is worthy of this thunderous applause.
是場足以接受這盛大喝采的引退賽
And to be the centre of attention like this…
居然能如此吸引眾人的目光
Congratulations,
恭喜妳…
Kitasan.
北部
Commendable.
真是厲害
Yes. As usual…
是的 像往常一樣…
No.
不…
I think this is her best performance yet.
我認為這是她 至今表現最好的一次比賽
What a shame.
真是可惜
I'm sure she can continue her career.
我覺得她還能再繼續下去的
You think so?
是這樣嗎
Huh?
咦
Quitting at this moment is a fleeting yet unforgettable beauty in itself.
我認為在這裡引退 讓她更有一種轉瞬即逝的美
I now see why you view her as your rival.
真不愧是妳的勁敵呢
Yeah.
是啊
Kitasan!
北部…
-Everyone is chanting Kitasan's name. -Kitasan.
-場內響起了呼喚北部之聲 -北部…
-And she waves in response too. -Kitasan!
-北部玄駒也揮舞著手回應粉絲們
Kitasan!
北部…
TRACEN ACADEMY OPEN DAY
(特雷森學園 校園開放日)
Please take a look.
請參考一下
Thank you.
謝謝妳
I'll show you the swimming pool next.
接著帶妳們去看看游泳池
Okay.
好…
In this academy, we focus on physical and formal education.
特雷森學園的校風 是文武兩道雙修的喔
Woah.
哇…
Awesome, right?
很厲害吧
This is as big as a real racecourse.
這裡跟實際比賽的競馬場 幾乎是一樣大的喔
Wow!
哇…
TEAM SPICA, JOIN US OR BE BURIED
(Team Spica 不加入就抓去埋)
You're here.
妳在這裡啊
"LET'S SHINE TOGETHER, TEAM CAPELLA" What are you doing?
(一起發光發熱吧 Team Capella) 妳在做什麼
We're all waiting for you.
大家都在等著妳喔
"LET'S SHINE TOGETHER, TEAM CAPELLA" Come.
(一起發光發熱吧 Team Capella) 我們走吧
Join us, Kita.
來吧 小北
Okay.
嗯
Were you spacing out?
妳在發什麼呆啊
That's not good.
這樣不行喔
It's spring. Where's your enthusiasm?
春天一到 就這麼沒有活力
I wonder what kind of horse girls we'll meet this year.
不知道接下來 會出現什麼樣的賽馬娘呢
I wonder too.
是啊